This question is simply crying out for recursion.
这个问题尤其需要用到递归
We're given a recursive formula for the Stirling numbers,
这里有个斯特令数递归公式
which is S(n, k) = kS(n - 1, k) + S(n - 1, k - 1).
即 S(n,k) = kS(n-1,k) + S(n-1,k-1)
What we need to think about, though, is the base case,
我们需要思考的是基础条件
which isn't given. When do we stop?
没有给出基础条件 何时停止呢？
Well, if we have some objects, and we want to split them up,
如果有一些物体 我们想要划分它们
if we have more piles that we're going to split them in,
如果群组多于物体数量
some pile will be empty. That's not allowed.
那么某些群组将为空 但是不能出现这种情况
That means that if we have more piles--
也就是如果有更多的群组
piles is the k and object is the n--
群组用 k 表示 对象用 n 表示
if we have more piles than objects, we want to return 0. We can't do it.
如果群组多于对象 我们就返回 0 不能出现这种情况
That's one case.
这是一种情况
If we look at our formula, we need to stop in other cases as well.
再看看我们的公式 我们还需要在其他情况下停止
We can't just return 0 all the time, because then our sum will be 0.
我们不能一直都返回 0 因为这样的话 我们的和将是 0
What happens when these two values are the same?
如果这两个值相等 会怎样？
Well, if the two values are the same.
如果这两个值相等
If n equals k, then how many ways are there of splitting up the objects into
如果 n = k 那么将物体分成数量相同的组
the same number of piles as there are objects? Well, there's just one way.
有多少种方式？
The other case we need to consider or we can consider, is if k is 1.
另一种需要考虑的情况是如果 k 为 1
What if we want to split the objects up into 1 pile?
如果要将物体分成一组 该怎么办？
Well, there is only one way to do that, so we can return 1 there as well.
只有一种方式 所以也返回 1
Now to look at the code, I'm just going to code those two conditions.
现在看看代码 我将只编写这两个条件
If we have fewer objects than piles, then there are no ways to arrange the objects.
如果物体数量小于群组数量 那么无法安排物体
If we have the same number of objects as piles or if we have just one pile,
如果物体数量等于群组数量 或者只有一个群组
then there's one way to do that.
那么只有一种实现方式
If we're in neither of those cases, then we're going to return the formula that we were given--
如果不是这两种情况 那么就要返回给定的公式
the recursive formula.
即该递归公式
That completes the Stirling number part of the question.
斯特令数问题就解完了
For the Bell numbers we just need to sum the Stirling numbers for k equals 1 up to n as stated.
对于贝尔数 我们需要对 k 等于 1 一直到 n 时的斯特令数求和
We need a variable to keep track of the total that we're going to return,
我们需要一个变量来存储我们将返回的总和
and then we need to step through the values of key from 1 up to n.
然后我们需要考虑 k 从 1 到 n 的情况
For k in the range 1 up to n + 1.
for k in range(1, n + 1).
Don't forget the +1 on the end, because range stops one before the second input number.
后面的 +1 别忘了 因为 range 在第二个输入数字之前停止
Then we just need to add the Stirling number n, k.
然后需要加上 stirling(n, k)
Finally, we need to return the total.
最后需要返回总和